Thor Lindberg

Reykjavík, Iceland

Email thor@lindberg.is

Website lindberg.is

Courses lindberg.is/certificates

GitHub github.com/thorlindberg

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg

Profile

M.Sc. Design with a background in the intersection between medical science and information technology. With this interdisciplinary perspective I act as a bridge between clients, design teams and development teams. This is evident from my consultancy experience, where I was involved in projects from initial analysis to design specification to planning development and implementing in code.

I invest my spare time in writing software, supplementing my education with courses, and traveling in the U.S. to network with others in tech.

Education

IT University of Copenhagen, 2022

Master of Science in Digital Design

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

Explorative design for typed JSON objects.

Relevant courses:

React Native mobile development with Expo.
 Advanced Design Processes. UX Design.

Copenhagen University, 2020

Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

 Qualitative analysis to determine low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims.

Relevant courses:

Statistics. Mathematical Modelling.
 Programming for Biosciences. IT Security.
 Medical Image Analysis. Interaction Design.

Skills

Language English (fluent), Icelandic (beginner)

Figma Components, variants, flows, auto layout

Software JSX, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI, Git

Analysis Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Data Excel, Visual Basic for Applications

Projects SharePoint, Azure, Office

Experience

Netcompany, 08/2022 - 12/2023

IT Consultant

- Lead the analysis and initial design phase of multiple client projects and authored feature and design documents.
- Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, and managing the project timeline and tasks.
- Provided clients with digital transformation strategies through analysis of business processes and IT infrastructure.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- Contributed to code optimization and new features for a React Native and React Native for Web application.

National Special Crime Unit, 10/2021 — 07/2022

IT-Administrative Student

- · Managed users of webportal and provided direct support.
- · Contributed to document processing architecture.
- · Authored documentation and website content.

IT University of Copenhagen, 08/2021 - 06/2022

Teaching Assistant

- · Assisted with teaching UX Design specialization.
- Assisted with assignments for courses in UX Design, Experimental Design, Python, and Javascript with MQTT.

Domino's Pizza, 08/2021 — 01/2022

Shift Leader

- Responsible for managing the store, closing the store, registering inventory, and matching store orders with use.
- · Delegated work to bakers and delivery drivers.
- · Primary pizza baker during rush hours.

Professional certificates

Mímir-simentun, 03/2024 - Now

Introduction to Icelandic

University of California, San Diego, 03/2024 - Now

Data Structures and Algorithms

Courses: Test-driven algorithm design. Dynamic programming. Advanced algorithms and data structures. Pattern matching.

Meta, 03/2024 - Now

Front-End Developer

Courses: JavaScript. Version control. HTML and CSS. Advanced React with components, hooks, APIs, and testing. UX/UI design.

Published

Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland

iPhone application (React Native) for exploring destinations in Iceland.

apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299